（レイツェル）失礼ねぇ。　これは　パズルよ。
Oh, come on. This is a puzzle.
ギヴァーは私。　ソルヴァーは君。→
I'm the Giver.
You're the Solver.
そして　財は…　真方ジン。
The treasure is Makata Jin.
[無線]（レイツェル）さあ　このパズルを解いて
私たちを見つけてごらんなさい。
Try solving the puzzle! Try finding us!
Why would you do this?
（大門カイト）
一体　何のために　そんな事を!?
[無線]ジンは俺たちに預ける…
そういう約束だったはずだ！
You promised you'd let us take care of Jin!
I promised?
約束？　フッ。
カイト…　君って　どこまでも
おめでたく　できてるのね。
Kaito, your naiveté is almost cute.
[無線]とても　ファイ・ブレインの子供たちとは
思えないくらい。→
Are you really a child of the Phi Brain?
君たちとの　お友達ごっこは
もう　たくさん！
I've had enough playing house with you guys.
私は　ジンと
２人の思い出をたどるわ。
I'll go and make new memories together with Jin.
私にとって大切なのはジンだけ。
He's the only thing I care about.
私は　ジンの記憶を…
そして　私のジンを取り戻す。
I'll return his memories and with them, the Jin I know.
[無線]私だけのジンを…。
（通話の切れる音）
The Jin who's all mine.
Kaito?
（井藤ノノハ）カイト…。
レイツェルが　ジンを連れ去った。
Raetsel took Jin and vanished.
She also challenged me to a puzzle with him as the treasure.
しかも　ジンを財にしたパズルを
仕掛けてきやがった。
That damn black cat girl...
（逆之上ギャモン）あの黒猫娘が…。
どうするつもり？　カイト。
What do we do now, Kaito?
Isn't it obvious?
決まってんだろ。
パズルを解いて　ジンを取り戻す！
I'm gonna solve her puzzle and take Jin back.
These are Jin's footprints from his missing year.
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）これが
ジンの空白の１年の軌跡…。
世界を舞台にした
壮大な　パズルタイムの始まりだ。
The stage is the entire world.
An immense puzzle time starts now.
うわ～！　テキサスって　だだっ広いね。
Whoa... Texas is so huge!
ったくよぉ～　広すぎて
人ふたり捜すとなると→
Way too huge!
It's so big I've got no idea how are we're supposed to find just two people here!
どっから手を付けたらいいのか
皆目　見当もつかねえぜ。
ここに間違いねえ。
（ノノハ　ギャモン）えっ？
This is the place.
ヒントは　レイツェルが送ってきた
その写真だけだろ。
But the only hint is that photo Raetsel sent, right?
でも　写真があるって事は　ここに
ジンさんがいたって事だよね。
But if the photo matches, that means Jin was here, right?
そんな簡単に解けるパズルを
レイツェルが仕掛けるはずはねえ。
There's no way Raetsel would let us have such an easy victory.
きっと
ここに　他のヒントがあるはずだ。
I'm sure there'll be other clues around here.
大丈夫だよ　カイト。
It's gonna be all right.
レイツェルさんは
ジンさんが大好きだもん。
Raetsel loves Jin.
傷つけたりはしないよ。
She'd never hurt him.
ああ。　俺も　そう思う。
Yeah, I agree on that.
Then what's the worrying about?
だったら
悩む必要なんかねえだろうがよ。
さっさと　パズルを解くまでだ。
ギャモン。
Just get this puzzle over with already.
Gammon...
勘違いすんな。
お前のためなんかじゃねえ。
Don't get me wrong.
I ain't doing this for you.
世界を舞台にした　パズル…
解くのは　このギャモン様だって事だ！
This is a puzzle that spans the whole world.
The great Gammon will be the one to solve it!
お前の力は借りねえ！
I don't need your help!
（ギャモン）てめえに力貸すなんて
言ってねえだろ！
何だと　この！
Who ever said anything about helping you?
What was that?!
Got a problem?
（ギャモン）やんのか　おい！
解くのは俺だ！
I'm gonna solve it!
Dream on, Kaitacos!
（ギャモン）何言ってんだ　こら！
この　タコスケ！
はいはい　そこまで。
あっ　泥棒！
ノノハ!?
Thief!
Nonoha!
（ギャモン）おわっ…　離せよ！
お前こそ！
Let go!
You first!
（スケボー男）ヘヘヘ…。
甘い！
Not a chance!
これでも　くらえ！
ぐはぁ～!?
Take this!
（カイト　ギャモン）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
ノノハのやつ　どこ行ったんだ？
≪勝手な事　すんな！
Where did Nonoha go?
Who do you think you are?
離してよ！
Let go!
What are you doing to Nonoha?!
ノノハに何しやがんだ！
ギャモン　待て！
Wait, Gammon!
この　ぬすっと野郎！
…ったぁ～。
This bastard!
うわっ!?
お兄ちゃん！
Brother?
ノノハじゃねえ!?
She's not Nonoha?
ジョーお兄ちゃんに　何すんのよ～！
（ギャモン）アッパーか！
What are you doing to my brother?!
Again?!
ぐはっ…。
ギャモン！
Gammon!
私の名前は　ノノよ！
My name's Nono!
You two really do look alike.
だけど　本当に　よく似てるな。
こうしてると　まるで姉妹みたい。
We could pass for sisters.
うれしいな！　私　ずっと
お姉ちゃんが欲しかったんだ。
I'm so happy. I've always wanted a big sister.
私も　妹ができたみたいで
うれしいよ。
Yeah, I'm happy that it seems like I got a little sister too.
（ノノ）ほんと!?
確かに　世の中には→
Really?
Sure, they say there are at least three perfect lookalikes out there for everyone,
自分と　うり二つの人間が
３人はいるっていうが→
それにしたって…。
but that doesn't make this any better.
Not to mention she's called Nono and I'm Nonoha. It's just a one syllable difference.
名前も　「ノノハ」と「ノノ」で
たったの１文字違いだし。
しかも　戦闘能力まで
ノノハ並みときてる。
And her CQC's Nonoha-tier too.
I'd say that uppercut was impressive if only the target hadn't been me.
さっきの　アッパーカットも
効いたのなんのって。
（ノノ）男のくせに
泣き言　言わないの。
キャイーン！→
Men shouldn't complain!
この～！
いきなり　デコピンすんじゃねえ！→
Hey! Don't just flick my forehead, dammit!
ったく　ノノハ並みの怪力の上に
こんな　いたずらっ子じゃ…。
Not only do you have Nonoha's monster strength, you tease too?
Who did you call a monster?
誰が怪力ですって？
（ギャモン）あは～　いや　その…。
I just—
（ノノ）ウフフッ。　ギャモン　だらしな～い！
（ギャモン）ほっとけ！
You're such a loser.
Give me a break!
（笑い声）
ん？　カイト　どうかした？
What's wrong, Kaito?
「ノノ」と「ノノハ」　あまりにも
似すぎてねえか？
Don't you think Nono and Nonoha just sound too alike?
What if it's Raetsel's trap—or just a piece of her puzzle?
まさか　レイツェルが仕組んだ　罠…。
いや　パズルのヒントかもしれねえ。
考え過ぎだよ。
You're over thinking it.
Is this a puzzle?
これって　パズル？
あっ。
ただの地図よ。
It's just a map!
カイトったら　パズル　パズルって…。
少し落ち着いてよ。
Kaito, you see puzzles in everything.
Calm down already.
ねえ？　ノノちゃん。
Right, Nono?
ねえ　ノノハ…
本当に　私のお姉ちゃんになって。
Hey, Nonoha, will you really become my big sister?
えっ？
ねえ　いいでしょ？→
It's fine, right?
私のお姉ちゃんになって
お兄ちゃんと３人で暮らそうよ。
Become my big sister and let's live here with my brother! The three of us together!
Not a chance!
な!?　ありえねえ…　あ　痛っ。→
どわ～！
（倒れる音）
もぉ～
ギャモン君。
大丈夫？
Come on, Gammon...
Are you okay?
Is this photo a hint?
この写真…　ヒントか？
Get over it already.
だから　そんなわけないでしょ。
ノノちゃんの　お兄さん？
Is this your brother, Nono?
Yeah. He was the captain of his high school's basketball team.
（ノノ）うん。　お兄ちゃん　高校の時
バスケチームのキャプテンだったんだ。
ケッ！　バスケだか　バカスケだか
知らねえが→
He must've left his balls in a basket then.
写真を全部しまってるって事は
大した活躍もしなかったんだろ。→
If he locked all these away, that means he got nowhere, right?
What a pain in the ass guy.
ったく…　はた迷惑な野郎だぜ。
（ジョー）それは　こっちの台詞だ。
That's my line.
（ノノハ　カイト　ギャモン）あっ。
（ノノ）お兄ちゃん。
Brother?
（ジョー）
言いがかりをつけてきただけじゃ
足りなくて→
Assaulting me like that wasn't enough? Now you're insulting me too?
今度は　バカ呼ばわりか？→
Don't get too full of yourself just cause I don't make a fuss!
黙ってりゃ
いい気になりやがって。
Get your filthy hands off me!
気安く触んじゃねえよ！
ああ!?　何だ　やるか！
Wanna go at it?!
（ギャモン）ムカつく野郎だぜ！
ちょっと　ギャモン君　やめなさいよ。
Stop it, Gammon!
You get on my nerves!
Don't, brother!
What was that?
ここにも
似たもん同士がいたってわけか。
So they're alike as well...
（ギャモン）
こうなったら　バスケで勝負だ！
Then let's fight with basketball!
てめえの得意なもんで
ぶっ潰してやるよ。
I'll beat you at what you're good at!
あ？　どうした
おじけづきやがったか？
What's wrong? Gotta change pants already?
とんだ腰抜け野郎だぜ！
What a scaredy cat!
何!?
What?!
ボールを持って　俺を抜けると思うな。
You thought you could get past me with the ball?
（カイト　ノノハ　ギャモン）あ…。
（ジョー）フン！
（ギャモン）おぉ…。
どりゃ～！　ど…!?
（カイト　ノノハ）あっ！
ねえ…　ノノちゃんの
お兄さんって…。
Nono, what's up with your brother?
He's a prodigy who was scouted by the US national team in high school.
高校時代は　全米から
スカウトが来てた花形選手よ。
ウフフフ…　やっぱり。
Thought so.
何!?
What?!
ハァ　ハァ…。
（ジョー）まだ続けるか？
Wanna continue?
Crap... I admit it. I lost.
くっそ～
分かったよ…　俺の負けだ。
てめえ　なかなか　やるじゃねえか。
You're damn good, dammit.
そういう　お前も
まあ　悪くはなかったけどな。
You weren't all that bad either.
言ってくれるぜ。　ヘッ。
Appreciate it.
わあ～。　お兄ちゃん　最高！→
You're really awesome, Brother!
You really should tryout for some pro team!
ねえ　やっぱり
プロバスケの入団テスト　受けてみようよ。
（ジョー）えっ？
今からでも遅くないって！
It's still not too late!
ノノ…　俺は　もう
バスケは　やめたんだ。
Nono, I've quit basketball already.
だけど…。
何回言えば
分かるんだ！
But—
How many times do I have to tell you?!
その話は　二度とするな！
Don't bring this up ever again!
お兄ちゃん…。
Brother...
That stupid brother of mine!
（ノノ）お兄ちゃんのバカ～！
It used to be his dream to become a pro player.
プロの選手になる事が
ずっと　お兄ちゃんの夢だったの。
実際　スカウトも来たんだろ？
He got scouted too, you said.
うん。
じゃあ　どうして…。
Then what happened?
去年　お父さんと　お母さんが
事故で死んで→
Our parents died last year in an accident.
お兄ちゃん
私が学校を卒業するまでは→
He decided to work my dad's old job until I've finished school,
お父さんの仕事を継ぐって言って
バスケ　やめちゃったの。
so he quit playing.
じゃあ　お前ら
きょうだい２人っきりなのか。
Then you two live alone?
（ノノ）うん。
ギャモン君とミハルちゃんの
ところと同じか。
Just like Gammon and Miharu...
（ノノ）お兄ちゃん
あんなに　バスケが好きなのに…。
He loves basketball so much too.
[無線]
Enigma?
エニグマ！
Hello?
だから　入団テストに
勝手に申し込んじゃったんだ。
But I signed him up for a team's tryout anyway.
お兄ちゃんには怒られたけど。
He got mad at me though.
それで　空港で　もめてたのか。
So that's why you were arguing at the airport?
No. I'm sure he appreciated it.
（ギャモン）ジョーは…　ノノの兄貴は→
ありがたいと思ってるぜ　きっと。
えっ？
He hides it by faking anger, because he can't show how happy he is.
そう思ってても　素直に
言えねえから怒ってごまかす。
じゃなきゃ…　かっこつかねえだろ
兄貴としては。
He can't act like your cool brother if he does.
ギャモンも　そうだったの？
Was it the same with you, Gammon?
（ギャモン）さあ　どうだったかな。
忘れちまったぜ。→
I wonder. I don't remember anymore.
What is this job of Joe's by the way?
で　ジョーが今やってる仕事ってのは
一体　何なんだ？
Puzzles. He's overseeing puzzles or something.
パズルよ。　パズルの管理人って
言ってた。
えっ！
何だって!?
What?
パズルを管理すれば
お金がもらえるんだって。
He said he gets money for managing puzzles.
It's this puzzle.
これが　そのパズルよ。→
He looks at this maze every day as if he was possessed by it.
お兄ちゃん　毎日　この迷路を
取りつかれたみたいに見てる。
（ギャモン）マジかよ　おい…。
Are you serious?
I'm scared of how he's been acting recently...
（ノノ）私　今のお兄ちゃんが
何だか怖くて…。→
I want him to return to how he used to be...
早く　元のお兄ちゃんに
戻ってほしいの。
ノノ。　この２人を見た事ねえか？
Nono, have you seen these two?
ううん　知らない。
そっか。
No. Never.
I see.
（バイクのエンジン音）
お兄ちゃん　帰ってきたみたい。
He's back.
お兄ちゃん。
Hey, Brother.
（ギャモン）ジョー。
Joe.
まさか　お前らが
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちだったとはな。
I wouldn't have guessed that you are children of the Phi Brain.
お前　もしかして…。
Don't tell me—
ああ。　マスターブレインだ。→
I'm a Master Brain.
真方ジンとの盟約に従って
全てのパズラーを　せん滅する。
As per the covenant with Makata Jin, we will annihilate all puzzlers.
今は　それが俺の夢だ。
That's my dream now.
So this maze is Raetsel's puzzle?
この迷路が　レイツェルのパズル…。
レイツェルのパズル？　何の事だ？
Raetsel's puzzle? What are you talking about?
とぼけんな！
とぼけるも何も→
Don't play coy!
I'm not playing anything. I inherited this puzzle from my dad.
そいつは　俺が
おやじから受け継いだパズルだ。
Though this is the first time I've actually come here.
もっとも　実際に　ここへ来るのは
初めてだがな。
何？
What?
（ジョー）昔は　馬２頭で競った
迷路だったらしいが→
I hear that back in the day, people raced in this maze on horses.
今は…　こいつで勝負だ！
But we're using these now!
お兄ちゃん　やめて！
せっかく仲良くなったのに。
Brother!
Stop it! We only just started to get along...
（ジョー）お前は関係ない。
This is none of your business.
Brother!
お兄ちゃん！
（ジョー）さあ　どっちが来る？
So? Which one of you will fight me?
俺が相手だ！
I'll take you on.
あっ…。
バイクも乗れねえくせに
出しゃばんな。
You can't even ride a bike. Get real, dude.
I'm the one in charge of bikes here.
バイクとくれば
俺しかいねえだろうがよ。
フッ。→
The maze is as shown on your helmet's visor.
迷路のコースは　ヘルメットのバイザーに
映し出されてるとおり。
Whoever gets to the goal first wins.
（ジョー）先に　ゴールしたもんの勝ちだ。
準備は　いいな。　まあ　勝つのは
俺と決まっているが。
何？
Are you ready? Though it's obvious that I'm gonna win.
What?
この迷路の事は
誰よりも俺が知っている。
I know more about this maze than anyone else.
Except my deceased father, that is.
死んだ　俺のおやじ以外はな。
どうする？　降りるんなら今だぜ。
So? This is your chance to back down.
誰が降りるかよ！　初めて迷路を
走るような初心者マーク野郎に→
As if!
The great Galileo won't lose to some newbie who's racing in this maze for the first time!
この　ガリレオのギャモン様が
負けるわけがねえ！
フッ。　後悔するなよ。
Don't regret those words.
What?!
何!?
（ジョー）負けた者には→
The loser gets "negro muerte"... an abyssal death!
ネグロムエルテ…　暗黒の死を！
うりゃ～！
（ギャモン）上等じゃねえか！
パズルタイムの…　始まりだ～！
Great!
Puzzle time starts now!
So you switched from basketball to making money using puzzles to support Nono?
ノノを養うために
バスケを諦めて　パズルで一稼ぎか？
How gallant!
ご苦労なこった！
うるせえ！
Shut up!
（カイト　ノノ　ノノハ）あっ。
（ギャモン）くそっ…。
Shit.
I'll do whatever it takes to win!
勝利のためなら
どんな手段も　いとわねえ！
I've got a little sister too, Joe.
ジョー！　俺にも妹がいてよぉ。→
パズルで　妹を養ってきた。
I supported her using puzzles.
You think you can beat me on your first puzzle time? Dream on!
その俺を　パズルぽっと出の
お前が負かすだと!?→
笑わせんな！
黙れ！
（車体の　ぶつかる音）
Can it!
お兄ちゃん！
Brother!
くっ…。　野郎！
Damn you!
な…!?　道が塞がってる。
The road's blocked?!
ブレーキが利かねえ！
The brakes don't work?!
このバイクは　ブレーキをかけても
止まらねえのさ。→
These bikes have their brakes rigged not to work
どちらかが勝つまではな！
until one of us wins, that is!
（ギャモン）野郎…。　な!?
Damn him.
ぶつかる！
（ノノ）キャー！
He's gonna crash!
Take this!
（ジョー）うっ!?
（ギャモン）てめえ…　生意気なんだよ！
Cheeky little bastard!
よかった。
Phew.
He has a chance if he uses the walls well enough.
この迷路　壁もうまく使っていけば
優位に立てるのか。
（ギャモン）「妹のため　生活のため」って
自分に言い訳して→
You gave up your dream with petty excuses like it's for your little sister's sake or your livelihood!
夢を諦めちまうような野郎が→
I'm not gonna let you get in front of me!
俺の前を走れるわけがねえ！
I'll show you that I can do it!
（ジョー）俺にだってできるって事を
証明してやるよ！
（ギャモン）ゲッ！　またかよ。
This again?
It doesn't matter how hard you try!
（ギャモン）おめえが
いくら頑張ったってなぁ→
The only thing you can prove is what a moron you are!
証明できんのは　せいぜい
お前のバカさ加減くらいだ！
ノノを…　妹を泣かしてまで
やりたい事が→
Can you really be proud of what you do if it makes your own sister, Nono, cry?
本当に　これだって
胸張って言えんのか!?
黙れ！
くはっ！
Fuck off!
Now I win!
（ジョー）これで　俺の勝ちだ！
お兄ちゃん　もうやめて～！
Stop it, Brother!
Nono...
あんなの…→
That... That isn't the brother I know!
あんなの　私の知ってる
お兄ちゃんじゃない。
Nono...
うっ!?　これが　マスターブレインの仕事？
This is the Master Brains' job?
Dammit.
くっそ…。
（ジョー）あいつ…　何考えてんだよ。
What the hell is he thinking?!
行き止まりだぞ!?
It's a dead end!
（ギャモン）うらぁ～！→
こうなったら…。→
At this point...
やつに勝つには　この手しかねえ！
This is my only way to defeat him!
諦めろ！　お前　死ぬぞ!?
Give it up! You're gonna die!
そうか！
I see!
Push that button! Then your bike will stop!
手元の　ボタンを押せ～！
そうすりゃ　バイクは止まる！
俺は…　諦めねえ！
I'll never give up!
（カイト　ノノハ　ノノ）あっ！
（ギャモン）ぐっ!?　くっそ～！
Shit!
うっ…　ふん～！
（ギャモン）っしゃあ～！
I win!
よ～し！
ふぅ…。
There!
うわ～!?
ジョー！
Joe!
お兄ちゃん！
Brother!
くっ…。　笑いたきゃ笑え。
Laugh all you want...
夢を諦めて　その上　このざまだと。
I gave up my dream and even ended up failing.
More like, you haven't really given up your dream and are ashamed of how you are now?
（ギャモン）夢を諦めてねえから→
今の自分を
ぶざまだと思うんじゃねえのか？
俺も　そうだったから
よく分かるんだよ。→
I was the same, so I understand.
おめえの本当の夢は　何だ？→
What's your real dream?
その夢を捨てても
ノノは喜ばねえぜ。→
Throwing it away won't make Nono happy.
I doubt you want to see her cry anymore.
おめえが見たいのは
ノノの涙じゃねえはずだ。
（ギャモン）夢を応援してくれる人が
いるのは幸せじゃねえか。
Isn't it great that you have someone to cheer for your dream?
だったら諦めんな！
Then don't give it up!
Put all you've got into challenging it!
思い切り　それに懸けて
輝いてみせろ！
（ノノ）お兄ちゃん。
Brother...
Nono!
お兄ちゃん！
Brother!
お兄ちゃんのバカ！
バカ　バカ。→
You're stupid! So stupid! Stupid!
バカ…。
（泣き声）
すまなかった　ノノ。
I'm sorry, Nono.
あれっ？
Huh?
何だろう…。
What's that?
数字？
Numbers?
You're leaving?
（ジョー）行くのか。
ああ。
Yeah. Those numbers are a latitude and longitude.
あの数字は　経度と緯度だ。
俺たちの捜してるやつらが
そこにいるかもしれないんだ。
The people we're looking for might be there.
そうか。　また　いつでも来てくれ。
歓迎するよ。
I see. Drop by anytime.
You're always welcome.
ありがとう。　ノノも元気でね。
（ノノ）うん！→
Thanks.
Take care, Nono.
I will.
ノノハも　私たち３人で暮らす気に
なったら　いつでも連絡してね。
If you feel like moving in with us, just give me a call, Nonoha.
おい！　そんな事より
バスケだろ　バスケ。
Basketball's the main point here!
This is the only way left for you now.
もう　お前に残されたのは
これっきゃねえだろうが！
かっこいい！
お…　おい…。
So cool!
Hey!
（ジョー）プロバスケのデビュー戦が決まったら
知らせる。　絶対　見に来いよ。
I'll let you know when my first pro game will be.
Be sure to come and see.
おう！　てめえの負けっぷり
見届けてやるぜ。
Sure thing. I'll enjoy seeing you lose!
Don't take me lightly!
ああ!?　ナメんな！
ヘッ　お前こそ。
That's my line!
What? Wanna go at it?
なにぃ？
やんのか！
They never learn.
懲りないなあ。
（ノノ）ほ～んと。
Yeah.
さあ　行くぞ！　ジンを捜しに！
Let's go and find Jin!
レイツェルのパズルを解いてやろうぜ！
Time to solve Raetsel's puzzle!
（エニグマ）ふ～ん…。
ま　構わんさ。
Ah, well. Whatever.
あの程度の男など　所詮　捨て駒だ。
That boy couldn't serve as more than a sacrifice anyway.
レイツェルのパズルは
まだ始まったばかり。
Raetsel's puzzle has only just begun.
Preview
Let's hurry and save Jin ourselves!
Welcome on board this POG Airlines flight.